welcome good to see you today we're
欢迎很 高兴见到你今天我们
going to begin transitioning from how
将开始从如何转变
our program interact with hardware to
我们的 程序 与硬件交互
how they interact with software in
如何与软件互动
particular system software and we're
特别是系统软件 和我们
going to start that investigation by by
要开始通过由调查
studying and learning about a process
研究和学习的过程
called linking which is how the system
所谓联是如何系统
builds builds your program ok so we're
建立构建你的程序 确定，所以我们
going to study the the process of
要学习的 过程
linking and then I'm going to show you a
链接，然后我要告诉 你一个
really cool technique called library
很酷的 技术，叫做库
inter positioning which it which allows
间的定位，它允许
you to use linking to actually intercept
您使用链接到实际拦截
on function calls in in in libraries
在函数调用在图书馆
like the standard c library so it's a
像标准C库 ，所以这是一个
very very powerful interesting technique
很好很强大有趣的技术
and it's all enabled by by linking so
这一切都使通过链接等等
let's start with a simple program this
让我们先从一个简单的程序这个
program consists of two modules of name
程序由名称的两个模块
dot c and some dot c some dot c takes as
点c 和一些C点一些C点的需要
an array as an argument and a length n
数组作为参数和一个长度为 n
and then it sums up the elements of that
然后将其总结了这些元件
array and returns the sum back to the
数组，并返回总和回
caller main dot c calls the sum function
来电者主要点C调用求和函数
using and passes it a two element array
使用，并将它传递一个两个元件阵列
of int and then returns that and then
INT，然后返回，然后
returns the value received from some we
返回从我们收到的一些值
that that's kind of an odd thing to do
那这是一种奇怪的事情
to return your your exit status like
来回报您的退出状态一样
that but we just did it so that the
那可是我们只是做了它 ，以便
compiler would not devise the way all of
编译器不会设计的方式，所有的
our code i know let's look at what
我们的代码我知道，让我们看看什么
happens if when we want to compile those
如果发生了，当我们想编译那些
those two modules for each of main dot c
这两个模块的每个主点的C
and some duck see the GCC calls a series
有的鸭 看到GCC调用系列
of translators on that on those modules
对这些模块的翻译
on those ducks c files first calls the c
这些鸭子的C文件首次调用C
preprocessor CPP
预处理CPP
then it calls the the compiler the
然后它调用编译器
actual compiler does which is CC one the
实际的编译器是CC的一个
compiler generates assembly which is
编译器生成组件， 其
then translated by the assembler AAS and
然后由汇编AAS翻译
resulting in a dot o file called main
导致所谓的主点o文件
dot o similar things happens first for
Ø点类似的事情发生了第一次
some dot C so after after the after
一些 C 点 后打完后
these three translators work on the code
这三个翻译上的代码工作
we have two object files two dot o files
我们有 两个目标文件的两个 点O文件
the linker takes those those dot o files
链接器将这些这些点O文件
and put some link them together sort of
并把一些 它们关联起来有点
smashes them together to form a single
摔破在一起以形成单个
executable called that we can then run
可执行 所谓的，我们可以再 运行
then we can then load and run on the
那么我们就可以加载并运行
system so the main dot C and some dots
系统，使主点 C和一些点
they are called source files these dot o
他们被称为源文件，这些点Ø
files are our object files that we are
文件是我们 是我们的目标文件
separately compiled but and we call them
单独编译但我们称之为
relocatable object files because they
重定位的目标文件，因为它们
can be combined together to form the
可以结合在一起以形成
fully linked executable object file so
完全挂钩的可执行目标文件，以便
why do we do it like this you know why
为什么我们不喜欢 这样 ，你知道为什么
why do we allow the so-called separate
为什么我们允许所谓的独立
compilation you know why don't we just
编译你知道我们为什么不 只是
have like one big you know one big file
有 就像一个巨大的，你知道一个大文件
that was all of our code in it well
这是我们所有的代码，它很好
there's a couple reasons the first is is
有一对夫妇的原因，首先是为
modularity so by by allowing you to
模块化所以通过允许 您
break your code into smaller pieces you
打破你的代码 成小块 你
can put related functions into separate
可以把相关功能集成到单独的
source files you can define libraries of
源文件可以定义库
function so it's just it's just good
功能，所以它只是这是一个好的
technique and it allows you to kind of
技术， 它可以让你 有种
break your code up into nice - nice
打破你的代码成 - 尼斯
modular pieces the other reason is
模块化件的另一个 原因是
efficiency
效率
so if
因此，如果
if we if we've broken up our program
如果我们如果我们已经打破了我们的计划
into multiple chunks if we change and if
成多块 ，如果我们改变，如果
we if we only need to change one of the
我们如果我们只需要改变的一个
chunks we don't have to recompile the
块，我们不必重新编译
all the other all the other modules
所有其他的所有其它模块
right we can just recompile the one
正确的，我们只需重新编译一个
module that we changed and then link
模块， 我们改变了，然后链接
them all together again right so it's
他们一起 再次右键 所以它的
it's efficient in time it's also
它的有效 时间它也是
efficient in space because you can take
高效的空间，因为 你可以采取
all of say all of the functions in the
所有的说 所有的功能 在
standard c library you could put them
标准C库，你可以把它们
all together but then the only functions
所有在一起，但随后的唯一功能
that you actually get compiled and
你实际上得到编译
linked into your program are the ones
链接到你的程序是那些
that you actually call okay so you can
你实际调用 好了，你 可以
you can save space you don't you know
你可以节省 空间，你难道你不知道
normally you use only a small subset of
通常只使用一小部分
the standard C functions and so there's
标准 C函数 等有
no there's no point in linking all of
没有有一个 在连接所有的 毫无 意义
those functions into your code if you
这些功能 集成到你的代码，如果你
don't need them all right so what are
不需要他们没事还等什么
linkers do well there's two main there's
接头搞好有两个主要有
two main tasks that linker performs the
链接器执行两项主要任务
first is called symbol resolution so
首先是所谓的符号解析等等
program define and reference symbols
程序中定义和参考符号
okay what the linker refers to as
没关系什么链接是指 为
symbols and these are global variables
符号，这些都是全局变量
and functions gain the names and those
和功能获得名字和那些
those objects they're referred to as a
他们被称为 那些对象
symbol so here we're declaring we're
符号所以在这里我们宣布我们
defining a symbol called swap here we're
这里定义符号称为交换 我们
referring when we call swap we're
当提到我们所说的交换我们
referring to that symbol okay that's a
指的 是符号没关系，这是一个
reference to the symbol and here we're
参考符号，在这里我们是
defining a pointer to an int called
限定的指针被称为一个int
XP so we're defining XP and we're
XP所以我们定义XP和我们
initializing it to the address of X so
它初始化为Ⅹ 的地址
we're referring that's a reference to X
我们指的是对X参考
okay so the symbol definitions are
好了，所以符号定义
stored in the object file by the
由存储的对象文件中
assembler in a symbol table which is an
汇编器在其为一个符号表
array of structs where each struck
结构的数组，其中每个 击中
contains information about the symbol
包含符号信息
like the name of the symbol its size and
像符号 的名称， 它的大小和
where it's located now what we mean by
它现在位于我们所说
symbol resolution is that during the
符号解析是， 在
linker blinking process the linker
连接 闪烁 过程中，连接器
associates each symbol reference with
关联与每个符号参照
exactly one symbol definition okay
正好一个符号定义好吗
so it's possible and multiple you know
所以这是可能的，你知道多
why is this an issue well it's possible
为什么这是 一个问题，那么它的可能
like in multiple modules you may declare
就像在多个模块可能会声明
a global variable with the same name the
具有相同 名称 的 全局变量
linker has to decide which one of those
连接器必须决定那些哪一个
definitions to use for all subsequent
定义用于所有后续
references
引用
now once once the linker is associated a
现在，一旦一旦接头相关的
unique object with each a unique symbol
与每个唯一的符号唯一的对象
definition with each reference then it
然后与每个参考定义它
does the second step which is relocation
确实第二步这是重新定位
and during relocation it merges all of
拆迁期间， 合并所有
the modules together into a single into
模块在一起成为单个成
a single executable object module that
一个单独的可执行的对象模块，其
can be directly loaded and executed on
可以直接加载和执行 上
the system so when it when it when it
系统所以当它的时候它时，它
does this merging it has to it has to
这是否合并有它有
figure out where each each symbol each
弄清楚其中每个的每个符号的每个
function and each variable is going to
功能和每个变量是要
be stored okay and this is called
存储 没关系，这 被称为
relocation because initially functions
搬迁因为最初的功能
are just stored at some offset in their
只是存储在一些抵消 其
in their object module because the the
他们的目标模块，因为中
linker doesn't know where those
链接器不知道那些
functions are actually going to be
功能实际上将 是
eventually a loaded into memory so
最后一个加载到内存中，因此
before before relocation the address of
前前搬迁的地址
a function in the object module is just
对象模块中的功能是刚好
its offset in the in the module and
其在模块中的偏移和
similarly for data during the relocation
类似地， 对于重定位期间的数据
step the the linker decides on where
步骤的链接器决定在哪里
each symbol is going to be ultimately
每个符号将是最终
located in memory one at X when the
位于存储器中的一个在 X当
program executes and it binds that that
程序执行，并绑定该说
those absolute memory locations to the
那些绝对内存位置的
to the symbol and then and then it goes
到符号，然后，然后 它去
and looks at all the references to those
并期待 在所有引用 那些
symbols and it updates those references
符号，它更新这些引用
so that they now they point to the
所以他们现在它们指向
correct address
正确的地址
okay so figure out where stuff is going
好了，所以找出 其中的东西 是怎么回事
to go for each definition figure out
去每个定义搞清楚
where it's going to go and for each
在那里它会 去为每个
reference then update that reference so
参照然后更新该参考所以
it now points to the right spot so let's
它指向正确的位置让我们
look at what what these how these steps
看看这些东西如何将这些 步骤
work in more detail before that we need
在此之前 ，我们需要更详细的工作
to we need to define a few things so
到我们需要定义一些东西，所以
there's there's three kinds of object
有有3种对象
modules that I've alluded to there's the
我已经提到有模块
dot o file which is a relocatable object
点o文件是可重定位目标
module this is the output of the
模块这是 的输出
assembler okay and it's it's not it's a
汇编很好，而且它这不是 它的一个
binary file
二进制文件
but it's not in any form that can be
但它不是以任何形式，可以是
directly loaded into memory it needs to
直接加载到存储器，它需要
be manipulated by the linker before it
前它由连接器被操纵
can be actually used there's the
可实际使用还有的
executable object file which is
可执行目标文件是
generated by the linker these are called
由连接器产生这些被称为
a doc files sometimes done historically
一个文档文件有时 做 历史
the very first Linux systems the
最先Linux系统
executable this sort of the default name
可执行这种默认名称
that they the developers of UNIX used
他们用UNIX的开发者
the default name for their executables
他们的可执行文件的默认名称
as they dot out so that's that's just
他们点了所以这是这只是
sort of a historical reason that it's
那种有历史原因的，它的
it's called a dot out and then there's
这就是所谓的一个点出来，然后有
another type of object file called the
另一种类型的对象文件的被称为
shared object file or dot iso file which
共享对象文件或点iso文件 ，其
is a sort of modern a modern technique
是一种现代的现代技术
for creating shared libraries and we'll
创建共享库，我们将
look at those we'll look at those later
看看那些我们来看看后来那些
today now
现在的今天
object modules come in a standard format
目标模块来以标准 格式
called elf formats and it's a unified
所谓的小精灵格式，它是一个统一的
format for dot o files for executables
对于可执行点O文件格式
and for dot iso files they all use the
和点 ISO文件他们都使用
same format the same general format so
相同的格式 相同的通用格式，以便
this while these these elf binaries are
这一点的同时，这些小精灵，这些二进制文件
their binaries they're very structured
他们的二进制他们很有条理
okay and they're broken up into section
很好，而且他们分成 部分
the at the beginning is the is a header
的开头是 一个首标
that defines things like the size of the
定义 喜欢的大小事
words the byte ordering whether it's a
词的字节顺序是否是一个
dot o and a dot out or a dot fo so it
点O和点出来或fo，从而它的点
just provides them some sort of general
只是为他们提供某种形式 的一般
information about this about this binary
这个关于这个 二进制 信息
and then there's what's a so called
然后有什么所谓 的
segment header table which is it only
段头表仅是它
it's only defined for the executable
它只是 对 可执行文件 中定义
object files and it indicates where all
目标文件， 它表明，所有
the different segments of the code are
代码的 不同段 是
going to go in in memory so where does
要去在内存中，以便在哪里呢
your stack go where do your shared
你的筹码去 哪里 做你共享
libraries go
图书馆去
where does your your initialized and
在哪里呢你对你的初始化，
uninitialized data where does your code
未初始化的数据在哪里呢代码
go right so all these all these various
向右走，因此所有这些所有这些不同
sections are defined in the segment
部分被 该 段中定义
header table and then there's the code
头表，然后有代码
itself which is is called the dot text
本身这就是所谓的点文字
section for sort of arcane historical
对于那种神秘历史的部分
reasons so dot text is always code and
原因所以点文字始终码
then that's followed by read-only data
那么，再接一个只读数据
such as the jump tables in switch
如 在开关跳转表
statements so text and and read only the
语句，使文字和， 只有读
dot text and ro data have the property
点文字和RO数据具有这样的性质
that they're they're both read-only you
他们是他们只读你
don't write to them then that's followed
不写他们那么， 再接
by the data section which is contains
由数据部分，其是含有
space for all of your initialized global
您的所有初始化的全局空间
variables and then there's a section
变量，然后有一个部分
called VSS which contain which defines
称为VSS 含有 其限定
the uninitialized global variables now
现在未初始化的全局变量
this doesn't actually take up any space
这实际上不占用任何空间
because they're uninitialized rates okay
因为他们未初始化率好
but they're their entries in the symbol
但 他们自己的符号项
table for them and and it's at when this
表他们和它在这个时
program gets loaded these variables are
程序被加载这些变量
going to need they're actually going to
将需要他们居然打算
have to have space allocated for them
必须有空间分配给他们
DFS is another one of those sort of
DFS 是 那些种类中的 另一
arcane names that goes all the way back
可以追溯到一路神秘的名字
to the 60s for there's an idea of
到20世纪60年代的有一个想法
instruction called block started by
指令称区块的开始
symbol I think a better way to remember
符号，我认为更好的方式来记住
what it means is better safe space okay
它的意思是更好的安全空间好吗
so you can if you have a separate
所以你可以，如果你有一个单独的
section for the uninitialized variable
用于未初始化的变量节
since then initialized you don't have to
从那时起初始化你不必
you don't have to not have to consume
你不必不必消耗
any room in the in the dot o file ok
任何房间 中 的点o文件 确定
there's also a section for the symbol
有也为符号节
table and this contained like I said
桌子， 这包含就像我说的
it's an array of structs for procedures
它的结构对程序的数组
global variables and anything defined
全局变量和定义的东西
with the static attribute and each one
与静态属性和每一个
of these each one of these symbols gets
这些这些符号中的每一个获得
an entry in the symbol table and then
在符号表中，然后一个条目
there's two two sections called them
有二两部分叫他们
that contain relocation info so this is
包含搬迁的信息，所以这是
the notes when that when the linker went
票据时，当链接去
and identified all the references to
并确定所有引用
symbols it put a little note to say I'm
符号它把一个小纸条说我
going to have to remember to fix this
要记得 要解决这个问题
the reference to the symbol up when I
该参考 符号，当我
when I actually create the be executable
当我真正创建可执行
so a relocation entry is just like a
所以重定位记录就像是一个
note that the linker or that it's a note
注意链接器或它的一个音符
that the assembler makes to the linker
该汇编程序的链接
to say hey you're going to have to fix
说嘿，你打算 要修复
up this this reference because I don't
了这个这个参考，因为我不
know I don't know where this symbol is
知道， 我 不知道这个符号是
actually going to be stored in memory
实际上将被存储在 内存 中
when it's when it's loaded
当它时，它的加载
okay and then there's a debug section
好吧，然后有一个调试节
that contains information that relates
包含 涉及 信息
line numbers to in the source code to
行号在源代码中 以
line numbers in the machine code okay
在本机代码行数好吗
and so this is called debug and this is
所以这就是所谓的调试，这是
what you get when you compile with dash
当你与 前围 编译你会得到什么
G and then there's a header table that
G和然后有一个头表
that tells you where all these different
告诉你在哪里所有这些不同的
sections start now to a linker there's
部分 现在开始到连接有
there's three different kinds of symbols
有三种不同类型的 符号
global symbols are defined in some
全局符号在一些定义
module m and they can and they can be
模块m和他们可以和它们可以 是
used by other modules all right so I
使用其他模块 没事 ，所以我
mean did you notice when we if we have a
意思是你有没有注意到，当我们，如果我们有一个
program that consists of multiple
程序 由多个的
modules and we compile each one of those
模块和我们编译那些中的每一个
modules into a dot o file will be
模块成点o文件将 是
calling functions that aren't defined
调用未定义的函数
that are defined by other modules right
由 右 其它模块中定义的
okay so those but there's no error
好了，所以那些，但没有错误
though that the compiler doesn't doesn't
虽然该编译器不会不
throw an error because it's assuming
抛出一个错误，因为它是假设
that those are defined in other modules
这些在 其它 模块中定义
and it assumes the linker will be able
它假定连接器将能够
to find them in and determine the
找到他们，并确定
address so anything that's defined with
地址，所以其与定义的东西
any global either either global variable
任何全球任一任全局变量
or a function name that's defined
或者某个定义的函数名
without the static attribute is a global
没有静态属性是一个全球性的
symbol okay now and then external
现在没事了，然后外部符号
symbols are kind of a flipside of that
各种符号的那种的 另一面
external symbols are symbols that are
外部符号是符号
referenced by some module but defined in
通过一些模块引用 但在限定
some other module okay so in our in our
其他一些模块好了，所以我们在 我们的
in our little running example when when
在我们的小运行例如 ，当时
main dot C called the function sum it
主要的 C点调用的函数总而言之
was referencing an external symbol okay
被引用的外部符号好吗
and then there's there's local symbols
然后还有有 局部符号
and these are symbols that are defined
而这些 中定义的 符号
and referenced within a module okay and
和一个模块内引用和好
those you create that this is not this
你所创建，这是不是这样
is different from local variables okay
从局部变量不同好吗
the linker you know local c variables
链接器要知道当地的 C变量
are
是
managed by the compiler on the stack
通过堆栈上的 编译器管理
linker has no idea about local local see
连接基不具有对当地地方 看到的想法
variables okay in this context when we
变量在这 方面 还好 ，当我们
talk about a local symbol what we're
谈论 一个局部符号就是我们
talking about is is either is a global a
讲的是要么是一个全球性的一个
global variable or function declared
全局变量或函数 声明
with the static attribute whose that can
与静态属性， 其 能
only be referenced from within that
只能从内引用
module so we say that the scope the
模块所以我们 说范围
scope of the func function or global
在 FUNC功能或全球 范围
variable defines what the static
变量定义什么静态
attribute is limited to the module that
属性被限定于模块
it was defined in okay so this is in C
它被定义好，所以这是用C
this is how we do abstraction and this
这是我们如何做到抽象与此
is how we can create sort of private
是我们如何能够建立某种私人
functions that and pup private functions
其功能和小狗专用功能
that can't be called from from outside
不能从外面叫
that module okay so for instance if we
该模块好了，例如，如果我们
want to make a library in C of functions
想使库 中的函数C
we want to make a collection of
我们要集合
functions that other programs can then
功能 的其他程序可以再
call and link into their program and
打电话联系到他们的计划和
call the functions that we want to make
调用我们要的功能
visible to to other programs are defined
可见 于其他程序的定义
without the static attribute and the
没有静态属性和
functions that we want to have private
我们希望有私人活动
and just be internal we declare what the
而仅仅是内部的，我们宣布了什么
static attribute and that way we get
静态属性， 这样，我们得到
abstraction and we get hiding
抽象，我们可以得到隐藏
information hiding and we're only
信息隐藏和我们是 唯一
exposing data and functions that that we
暴露的是我们的数据和功能
want that we want to expose all right so
希望， 我们要 揭露一切权利，使
let's look in detail how the symbol
让我们来详细看一下如何 符号
resolution step works we recall our
分辨率步工作我们回顾
example our example program
例如我们的 示例程序
so here we're referencing a global
所以在这里我们引用一个全球性的
called array that's defined within Maine
多数民众赞成内缅因州定义称为数组
dot see here when we here we're defining
点这里看到，当我们在这里我们定义
Maine a global called Maine here we're
缅因州全球名为缅因州 这里我们
referencing a global called some that's
引用全球叫一些这
defined in some dot C and Val is a local
在一些C点定义和Val是本地
C variable on the stack and linker knows
栈和接头 上C变量 知道
nothing about that
任何有关
okay now nor does it know anything about
现在没事了，也不知道什么
IRS which are also local variables now
IRS 这也是现在局部变量
let's just let's make sure that we
我们只是让我们确信 我们
understand the difference between local
了解当地的区别
static C variables versus local non
静态C变量与当地的非
static C variables so here we're
静态C变量所以在这里我们
defining a local static variable called
定义称为本地静态变量
int within this function f now because
这个函数中诠释第 f 因为
it's local its scope is limited to this
这是当地的范围仅限 于这
function so this variable X can only be
功能，所以这个变量 X只能是
referenced within function f and
函数f中引用和
similarly for this definition of X and
同样，对于这个定义X和
function G can only be referenced by by
函数G只能通过引用
function G now what's but because it's
函数G现在有什么，而是因为它是
declared with the static attribute it's
与静态属性，它的声明
not stored on the stack it's actually
不存储在堆栈上它实际上
stored in in the in dot data just like a
存储在中就像 一个 点数据
global would be so it's it's like a
全球会因此它它就像一个
global in a sense that it's actually
全球在 某种意义上说，它实际上是
stored in data rather than the stack but
存储在 数据而不是堆叠但
it's like a local C variable in the
这就像在一个局部C变量
sense that its scope is limited just to
感觉它的范围 只是 局限于
the function that it's defined in so
它在 这样 定义的函数
what what the compiler will do it will
什么什么，编译器会做它会
allocate space for each definition of X
对于X的每个定义分配空间
so this and it'll give it some name to
所以这一点， 它就会给 它一些名字
disambiguate it so maybe it will call
它的歧义，所以也许它会调用
this one X dot 1 and maybe this one X
这一个X点 1，也许这一个 X
dot 2
2点
so these symbols are allocated in dot
所以这些符号 在点 分配
data because because they're initialized
数据，因为，因为他们正在初始化
and they get symbol table entries just
而他们得到的符号表项 只
like just like any other symbol okay so
像就像任何其他符号好 了，
I said that during symbol resolution the
我说，符号解析的过程中
linker associates each reference each
接头将每个 引用每个
symbol reference to exactly one unique
符号参照正好一个独特
symbol definition now how does it do
现在符号定义， 它是如何做
that if there's multiple symbol
如果有多个符号
definitions across all the modules so to
在所有模块定义，以便于
understand this will will will will
了解这样做会会会将就
define symbols as being either strong or
定义的符号为是强或
weak so strong symbols are either
弱如此强大的符号或者是
procedures or function function names or
过程或函数的函数名或
initialize global variables weak symbols
初始化的全局变量弱符号
or uninitialized global variables okay
或者未初始化的全局变量好吗
so int foo here is a strong symbol
所以这里INT foo是一个强有力的象征
because it's initialized we're
因为它的初始化 我们
initializing it p1 is strong by
初始化它P1 是由强
definition foo is is weak in p2 dot C of
定义foo是处于 P2 C点弱
this this definition of foo is weak
FOO的这此定义为弱
because it's uninitialized and the
因为它的初始化 和
definition of p2 is strong okay so that
P2的定义是强没关系，这样
the rules that the velinkar uses are the
该velinkar 用途的规则
following multiple strong symbols not
以下多个强符号不
allowed so that's an error okay
允许这样没关系的错误
so that means that if we if across
因此，这意味着，如果我们如果通过
multiple modules we declare a function
多个模块，我们声明函数
with the same name the linker will will
具有相同名称的链接器将将就
throw an error that's not allowed
扔了不允许使用的错误
given a strong symbol and multiple weak
给予强烈的符号和多个弱
symbols if the linker will always choose
如果链接器总是会选择符号
the strong symbol now remember if we
现在强大的符号记住，如果我们
initialize a global variable and we if
初始化一个全局变量， 如果我们
we declare a initialized global variable
我们声明了一个初始化的全局变量
across multiple modules that's an error
在多个 模块这是 一个错误
because those are strong symbols okay by
因为这些都是强烈的符号 由好吗
rule one but if we have one strong
规则之一，但如果我们有一个强大的
symbol and multiple weak symbols all
符号和多个弱符号的所有
with the same name then the compiler
用相同的名字， 那么编译器
will choose the
将选择
strong symbol okay and it will associate
强大的符号没关系，它 会联想
all references to that symbol will go to
该符号的所有引用会去
that strong symbol and if there's
那强大的象征，如果有
multiple weeks in both then it just
多个星期在这两个那么它只是
picks an arbitrary one and this thisthis
挑选任意一个，这thisthis
will see can be problematic
会看到可能 有问题
now you can override it with this GCC
现在你可以用这个 GCC 覆盖它
flag called no common and if you if you
如果你，如果你叫旗没有共同的和
declare your function with this no
与此声明你的功能无
common argument then multiple weak
普遍的说法则多个弱
symbols will throw an error in the
符号将扔在一个错误
linker all right so why do we care about
连接没事那么为什么我们 关心
all this stuff well it turns out if
所有这些东西以及事实证明 ，如果
you're not aware of this stuff you can
你不知道的 这个东西，你可以
you can run into some really serious
你可以运行了一些很严重
problems that are just perplexing and
这只是令人困惑的问题，
confounding right so linker linker
混杂权利，使连接器连接器
errors are like the worst kind they're
错误是像他们最坏的一种
the hardest kind of debug because people
在最难的 调试，因为 人们 的
aren't usually aware of what's going on
通常不知道发生了什么事情的
inside their linkers and usually it's
里面的接头， 通常它是
only like the very best programmers that
只喜欢最好的程序员
really understand you know how these
真正了解你懂得这些
linkers work and what kind of errors
连接器的工作，什么样的错误
they can throw and how to debug them so
他们可以抛出以及如何将它们调试等等
let me show you some examples of these
让我告诉你其中的一些示例
these kind of errors all right so we
这些样的错误没事，所以我们
have a program we've worked we have two
有我们的工作程序 ，我们有两个
modules so each of these rectangles
模块所以每个这些矩形的
corresponds to a module and we're
对应于一个模块和我们
defining p1 in each module so that's too
每个模块中定义P1，这样太
strong symbols that's an error okay
强大的符号这是一个错误没关系
now here we were defining p1 and p2 so
现在我们在这里被定义 p1 和 p2等等
we're okay but now we've got two week
我们准备好了，但现在我们已经有了2周
symbols both are integers variables
符号都是整数变量
called X so and if these modules are
所谓X所以，如果这些模块
referencing X the linker will just pick
引用X连接器将只挑选
it we'll just pick one of these to serve
它我们就 挑其中的一个服务
as the definition but is this really
作为定义，但是这是真的
what you want now in this case it
你现在 要 在这种情况下是什么
doesn't really hurt anything because X
并没有真正伤害任何东西，因为X
is declared in both modules is an int
在这两个模块被声明是 int
all right so it'll just be it'll just be
没事所以它会只是它会只是
some integer sized variable that and it
一些整数的尺寸变量和它
will be it'll be somewhere and but it
将是这将是地方和 ，但它
doesn't really matter which which one
并不重要， 这其中一个
the linker chooses but we start to get
链接器选择，但我们开始 得到
into trouble if we declare these weak
陷入困境，如果我们声明这些 弱
symbols with different types so here
不同的类型，因此这里的符号
we've declared an int X in one module
我们已经声明一个模块在一个int X
and a double X in another module so if
而在另一个模块，所以如果双X
we write to X if the linker just
我们写信给X如果链接只是
arbitrarily chooses this this symbol
这个任意选择该符号
definition to use now this is a symbol
定义现在使用的，这是一个符号
that of length 8 of size 8 if we
该长度8的尺寸为8，如果我们
anywhere in this program if we if the
在这个程序的任何地方，如果我们 如果
linker chooses that then anywhere in the
链接器选择是，然后在任何地方
program those references to those
编程那些那些引用
references to X will be to this double
到X引用将是这双
word this double word even even in this
这个字双字甚至即使在这种
module if we reference X it'll be an 8
模块如果我们引用X这将是一个8
byte right so it will overwrite Y with
字节右所以 它会覆盖Y中
the
该
hi order excuse me oh no it's completely
。为了对不起哦不，它是完全
its system it'll just pick one
它的 系统，它会随便挑一个
arbitrarily and you don't know I mean it
随意而你不知道我是认真的
alright here's now this is uh here's the
好吧这里的现在，这是呃 ，这里的
problem we've defined a strong symbol X
问题我们定义了一个强有力的符号X
because we initialize it so the linker
因为我们初始化它因此链接
will always will associate all
总会将所有关联
references to X to this integer size
这个整数大小 X引用
this integer sized symbol so if we write
这个整数大小的符号，所以如果我们 写
oh yeah right so so rights to X here
噢权利，使这样的权利X这里
this will be a double in this module but
这 将是一个双本模块中，但
it will overwrite Y in this module so
它会在此模块中覆盖ÿ 如此
that's really nasty
这真是可恶
and here we were defining a strong
在这里，我们定义了一个强大的
symbol X so references to X in the
符号X所以在以X引用
second module will always get it will
第二模块总是会得到它会
refer to this initialized variable which
参考此初始化的变量，其
might not so it might not be what you
可能没有那么它可能不是 你
want you may you may be assuming that
希望你可以，你可以假设
it's uninitialized in your code okay and
它未初始化 代码中的好和
then you get the the ultimate nightmare
那么你得到的终极噩梦
scenario suppose you know because we're
情景假设你知道，因为我们是
following a standard adi we can compile
按照标准ADI我们可以编译
our code with multiple compilers and
我们的代码有多个编译器 和
this actually happens in some oh yes
这实际上发生在一些哦，是的
questions oh yeah actually you're right
问题噢其实你是对的
it will it will still take preference
它会仍然会采取优先
and you'd be writing a for by quantity
你会 通过数量 来写
which is is what you want so that slides
这是你想要的， 这样的幻灯片
not quite right so yeah what is the
不完全正确所以是什么
point of doing that expert is not that
这样做 ，专家观点并不是 说
it is always being reference just
它总是被 引用只要
locally in your function what is the
在本地的功能是什么
point of declaring it back is it
声明 回来 的一点 是它
distorted in like so no no no it's if
扭曲 的像 这样没有没有 没有它，如果
you reference up if you reference a a
你参考， 如果你 引用AA
variable that's you need so a variable
变量这就是你需要这么一个变量
its defined in your module and then you
它 在你的模块，然后定义你
with the static right oh they're both
与静态权哦，他们俩都是
they're both local so you do this if you
他们都是当地的，所以你如果你这样做
want a value to retain from if you want
希望的值时， 如果你想 保留
if you want that variable to retain
如果你想该变量 保留
value from in locations in location so
从在位置的位置，以便值
suppose you it's usually a bad idea as
假设你它通常是一个糟糕的主意， 因为
we'll see when we study threads because
我们会看到，当我们学习，因为线程
it makes your code non thread safe but
它使你的代码非线程安全的，但
like early like random number generators
像早期一样随机数生成器
would it would compute a pseudo-random
将它会计算 一个伪随机
number and then it would store it in a
号码，然后将其保存 在
static variable and then use that as the
静态变量，然后用其 作为
starting value for the next the neck
在接下来的颈部起始值
time you called that function so
时间你们称为功能，所以
whenever you want values to persist
每当你想值持续
across function invocation to reduce
在函数调用，以减少
static yes
静态是
well win it let me let me get this
顺利拿下它让我让我 得到 这个
straight right 2x + t2 will actually
直右2X + T2 实际上会
correspond to the memory look that will
对应于存储器看即会
actually go to the memory location I'm
其实去的内存位置 我
sorry I I need to amend that so write 2x
对不起，我我需要 修改的是这么 写的2倍
in t2 will be 8 bytes because the
在t2中将会因为 8个字节
compiler you know the compiler knows
编译器 知道编译器知道
that it's a double but it'll go to a
这是一个双，但它会去
memory location that I that's only 4
内存位置，我这只是4
bytes because X because the linker chose
字节，因为 X因为链接选择
the strong symbol okay so so the rights
强大的符号好了，所以这样的 权利
to X and T 2 will actually overwrite Y
以X和T 2实际上将覆盖ÿ
ok
好
I'm sorry yes question that's just
对不起，是的问题，这只是
usually the way it happens you know no
通常它发生的方式，你 不知道
no no global variables go in in dot data
没有没有全局变量去在点数据
they don't go on the stack but usually
他们不进入堆叠，但通常
if you define local variables in a
如果你定义一个局部变量
function it will put them it will
功能就会把他们它将
allocate them one after the other on
它们分配一个其他后
their on the stack okay
他们在栈上好吗
all right so all this discussion about
没事所以 这一切的讨论
these weird strong weak symbol rules
这些奇怪的强弱符号规则
that the linker have it's another reason
链接器有 它的另一个原因
to avoid global variables if you can if
避免全局 变量，如果你可以的，如果
you if you need to declare a global see
你是否需要声明一个全局看
if you can declare it static because
如果你可以把它声明静态的，因为
that'll limited scope to the the module
那将限制范围的模块
that it's declared in so that's a good
， 它的宣告所以这是一个很好的
idea if you can do it and if you define
主意，如果 你能做到这一点 ，如果你定义
a global variable initialize it so that
一个全局变量初始化，使
you'll you'll you'll find you'll
你会，你会，你会发现你会
discover if you have multiple initialize
发现如果您有多个 初始化
global symbols with the same name in
具有相同名称的全局符号
your code and then if you want to it's
你的代码，然后，如果你想它是
always good practice if you're
总是好的做法，如果你是
referencing an external variable to tell
引用外部变量来告诉
the compiler about it by using the
关于它的编译器使用
extern attribute all right so now at
没事 所以现在 的extern属性
this point the linker has associated
这一点上，链接器相关
every symbol reference with some symbol
一些符号每个符号参考
definition now it has to take all those
定义现在它必须采取所有这些
object relocatable object files and
对象重定位目标文件和
smush them together and create like one
斯马什在一起，并创建一个类似
one big executable so suppose with our
一个大的可执行文件等等假设我们
example a little running example each
例如有点运行实例中，每个
main zero and some dot o contain a a
主要零和一些点Ø包含 一个
code and initialize data some dato
代码并初始化数据的 一些达托
doesn't have any initialize data just
没有任何初始化 只是 数据
has code and then there's their system
有代码，然后有自己的系统
code that actually runs before and after
实际上之前和之后运行的代码
your program so when when your program
你的程序故当你的程序
run it actually starts executing
运行它实际上开始执行
a startup code from from would see that
从会看到一个启动代码
that sort of initializes things and then
诸如此类的事情进行初始化，然后
the last thing that it does is it calls
它确实的最后一件事是 调用
main and passes it arcs RC and RV okay
主要并将其弧RC和RV 好吗
and then when your when your program
然后当你当你的程序
exits well that this is call but if your
退出 清楚 ，这 是 呼叫，但如果你的
program if your main function routine
程序如果你的主函数程序
does a return then it returns back to
做一回则返回 到
that startup code which then doesn't
在启动代码， 然后不
exit okay so so this is just and so this
退出好了，所以这只是所以这
this consists of fudge
这包括软糖
texts and data as well and so when we
文本和 数据，以及，所以当我们
when the linker relocates these these
当链接器重定位这些这些
object files it takes all of the the
目标文件需要的所有的
code the text sections from each of the
从各代码中的文本段
modules and put them together
模块和 把它们放在一起
contiguously in the dot text section for
连续在 点文字 部分
the executable object file ok so it just
可执行的目标文件确定，所以它只是
puts them together in some order that it
把它们放在一起以某种 顺序，它
determines and it creates a combined dot
确定并创建一个合并点
text section in the executable that
可执行文本节
contains all of the system code and the
包含了所有的系统代码和
all of the all of the code defined in
所有在所有定义的代码的的
the modules and then it does the same
模块，然后它同样的
thing with the data takes all the all
与数据 的东西 通吃所有
the dot data sections from the various
来自各个点的数据段
object files and puts them together in
目标文件和把它们放在一起
one combined data section in the
在一个组合数据部
executable and it also emerges the
可执行文件，它也将出现
symbol tables and in the debug
在调试符号表和
information as well now when it just the
信息以及现在当 它只是
act the act of sort of relocating these
这类行为，这些搬迁的行为
these object files requires the linker
这些目标文件， 需要链接
to figure out where it's going to
揣摩出它要
actually store these these these
实际存储这些这些这些
different these different symbols when
不同这些不同的符号 时
the system gets when this program gets
这一计划得到当系统变得
loaded so it it has to pick an address
加载所以它必须 选择一个地址
for main that that function will start
主这项职能将启动
at some absolute address it's going to
在一些绝对地址这将
have it's gonna have to do the same for
有 它的 会都来为他们做同样的
swap so for all the all the data arrays
交换所以对于所有的全部数据阵列
right
对
and but the problem is that when this
而但问题是，当这个
code is is compiled the compiler doesn't
代码被编译，编译器不
know what addresses the linker is going
明确知道哪些地址链接是怎么回事
to pick so the so the compiler creates
挑所以这样编译器创建
these these reminders to the linker
这些这些提醒链接
called relocation entries which which
所谓的重定位项哪家
are then stored in the relocation
然后存储在搬迁
sections of the the object file and
的对象文件的部分和
these these relocation entries are
这些搬迁这些条目是
instructions to the linker that's
到这就是链接程序指令
something that there's a reference to a
一些有一个参考
symbol that's going to have to be
那将必须符号
patched up when the the code is actually
修补了当的代码实际上是
relocated and merged into the executable
搬迁并合并到可执行文件
so let's look at a couple of these a
所以让我们来看看一对夫妇它们的的
couple of examples so in our in our main
几个 例子，让我们在我们的主
dot c module there was a reference to
点C模块中有一个参考
this to this global symbol called array
这对这一 全球性符号 称为数组
okay and then there's also a reference
好吧 ，然后也有一个参考
to this this this global symbol sum
到这这这全局符号总和
which is the function so the the
这是为了让该功能
compiler creates two relocation entries
编译器创建两个定位项
the first one for the reference to the
第一个为所述参考
array a so here we're moving remember
数组所以在这里我们正在记
EDI is the first argument so remember
EDI是第一个参数所以记住
our sum function takes the address of
我们和功能需要的地址
the of array of the input array as its
的输入数组作为阵列的其
it's argument so this move we're moving
它的参数 ，所以这招我们正在
the address of the array into EDI for
数组的地址转换成EDI用于
the first argument but the compiler
第一个参数，但编译器
doesn't know what that address is going
不知道该地址是怎么回事
to be it's it just it just it just it
是它只是是它 只是它 只是它
just moves in it an immediate value of 0
只是在它移动 的0 立即值
into EDI temporarily right so you can
到EDI暂时 的权利 ，所以你可以
see this is all zeros but bf is the move
看到这一切都是零，但BF是举
instruction and then there's allsey ROS
指令，然后有allsey ROS
in for now
在现在
and then it places this relocation entry
然后它把这个重定位项
in the in the relocation section of
在在搬迁部
Maemo and it it says it says to the
Maemo操作它，它说，它说的
laker at addre at offset a so these let
在 addre 湖人 以 抵消所以这些都让
me remind you these are our main zero
我提醒你，这些是我们的主要 零
module only contains one one function so
模块只包含一个一个功能，所以
that function starts that offsets zero
该功能将启动零偏移
in the in the code section of the module
在在模块的代码部分
in the dot text section of the module if
在模块如果点文字部分
there were other functions in this
还有其他的功能，在这
module they would they would follow
模块他们自己也跟着
immediately after okay and it so you can
之后 好，它让你可以
see what what the compiler is it's just
看看编译器是什么，它只是
all it it's just generating offsets of
所有它，它只是产生的偏移
these instructions from the beginning of
从一开始这些指令
the dot text section and it it includes
点文字部分，它包括它
this relocation entry which says to the
这个搬迁进入它说的
link or hey on when you're relocating
当你在搬迁链接或嘿嘿
main zero at offset a in this dot text
在这点 文字 主要 在零点 偏移
section you've got a reference a 30 to a
部分中，您已经有了一个 参考 30 到
reference to an array in the form of a
参考阵列中的形式
32-bit address ok so that so eventually
32位地址 确定，以便所以最终
the linker is going to have to patch up
链接器将不得不修补
these so this is address nine this is
这些，所以这是解决9，这是
address a it's going to have to patch up
地址这将有修补
the four bytes starting at address a
四个字节开始地址的
with the absolute address of the symbol
与符号的绝对地址
array
排列
and then similarly the reference to the
然后类似地，参考
reference to this the reference to this
参照该参考此
function some the compiler has no idea
功能等一些编译器不知道
where some actually will end up it
其中一些实际上将结束它
doesn't even know what module it's in or
甚至不知道它在什么模块或
even if it's even it is defined in a
即使它即使 它是在一个定义
module so in this case it just it does a
模块所以在这种情况下，它只是把它做了
call with all zeros and then it adds the
与所有零打电话，然后将 其添加
three location entry that says to the
3个地点条目的说
linker at offset F you've got a four
在连接器偏移F你已经有了一个四
byte PC relative reference to a function
字节PC相对引用的功能
to assemble called some and then it this
组装叫一些，然后 这个
is sort of a arcane detail that but and
是不大不小的神秘细节这一点，但并
it includes there's an option to include
它包含有一个选项， 包括
a bias in the in the offset and since
在中偏移和自偏置
we're using since calls are since calls
我们使用，因为电话是因为电话
are always resolved using PC relative
使用 相对 PC 总是解决
addressing the value that's going to be
寻址将是值
placed here at these four bytes that
这里放置在这四个字节表示
offset F is going to be an offset from
偏移F 将 是 从偏移
the current RI p value or programmer
当前RI的p值或 程序员
counter value and since the program
计数器值，因为程序
counter always points to the Ness cat
柜台总是指向内斯 猫
next instruction it includes this which
下一个指令，它包括此其
is four bytes away it includes this this
是四个字节远它包括这个这个
offset of minus four so if it I talked
零下四个偏移所以如果 我 跟
about it in detail in the book if you
它在 书，如果你 详细
really want to know how this works but
真正想知道的是如何工作的，但
just the point here is that there's
只是这里的关键是，有
enough information for the linker to
足够的信息， 链接器
actually fill in the right address so
在正确的地址实际上填补如此
now if we look at the relocated text
现在，如果我们 看一下搬迁文本
section so if we if we compile this code
部分因此，如果我们如果我们编译这段代码
into an executable and then we use off
为可执行文件，然后我们用关闭
stump to to disassemble it then
树桩拆开它，然后
what you see is this this reference here
你看这是什么在这里这个参考
where we move the address of the address
我们移动地址的地址
of a into EDI those four bytes which
的成EDI那些四个字节，其
were originally zero has now been
最初 的零 到现在已经
updated with the the actual address of
用的实际地址更新
array in in memory at runtime okay so
阵列中的存储器中运行时 好了，所以
the linkers decided that the array is
接头决定阵列是
going to go at address zero x six zero
要去的地址 零个六零
one zero one eight and then it's it's
一个零点一八，然后是它的
actually patched that the four bytes in
实际上修补， 在四个字节
the cup in the in the move instruction
杯在中移动指令
with that absolute address and the call
与绝对地址和电话
to Psalm is it's also been updated but
诗篇是它也 一直 在 更新，但
this one's interesting right that so the
这一个有趣 正确的，所以
the address it's been updated with the
它已经更新与地址
PC relative address of five okay so when
5没关系的PC相对地址，所以当
this program run this call instruction
该程序 运行这个调用指令
what it will do when it when it
它会做，当 它时，它
determines when it computes the absolute
确定何时它计算绝对
address of of the function some it will
功能的地址一些它会
take
采取
it will take the current value of the
将采取的当前值
program counter which is the next
程序计数器是下一个
construction so 4 0 0 43 and it will add
施工 所以 4 0 0 43和它将增加
to it whatever whatever value is in this
它 无论任何 值在此
immediate field okay which is a tooth
立即字段还好这是牙齿
comprar today's a tooth compliment
今天 comprar 是 牙齿 恭维
integer so it can go it can be relative
整数因此它可以去它可以是相对的
you can go - or or plus in this case
你可以去- 或者或 加在这种情况下，
it's saying that the function that you
它 说 ， 该函数 ，你
want to call is that it is at 4 0 0 4 e
要调用的是， 它是在 4 0 0 4 E
3 + 5 which is 4 0 0 for e 8 which is
3 + 5，它是4 0 0为E 8是
the address of some okay and so the
一些好等等的地址
linker the linker does that the compiler
链接链接程序编译器
has all the smarts the compiler computed
拥有所有 的编译器计算 出的智慧
the relocation entry the linker is just
搬迁进入的连接仅仅是
blindly going through each of those
通过各那些一味去
relocation entries and just doing what
重定位项，只是在做什么
it's told ok but the net result is that
它告诉确定，但最终结果是，
now all of these these references have
现在所有这些这些引用
been patched up with with valid absolute
被修补了与绝对有效
addresses
地址
now once the linker has created a an
现在一旦连接创造了一个
object file that object file can be
该目标文件目标文件可以
loaded the code and data and that object
加载的代码 和数据，并且 对象
file can be loaded directly into memory
文件可以被直接加载 到存储器
with with no further modification okay
与没有进一步修改好
so the if you look at all of the
所以，如果你看一下所有的
read-only sections in the executable so
只读的可执行部分，从而
there's this an it section which we're
有这样一个IT部分，我们是
not to worry about that that all the
不要担心 所有 的
code is in the dot text and things like
代码是在点文字之类的东西
jump tables or an ro data all of this
跳转表或RO数据所有 这 一切
data can be loaded directly into memory
数据可以直接被加载到存储器
as is okay so these bytes can just be
因为是好了，这些字节可以只是
copied directly into into memory and
直接复制到到存储器中和
that that forms is so called a read-only
这将形成的所谓的一个只读的
code segment the the data and the dot
代码段中的 数据 和点
data and BSS deck X section can also be
数据和BSS 甲板X部 也可以是
copied directly into into memory and in
直接复制 到到存储器和在
the case of the variables and data
所述变量和数据的情况下
they'll be initialized to a value that's
他们会 被初始化 ，这是 一个价值
stored in the symbol table so
存储在符号表中，以便
we're drawing our our memory here this
我们在这里这提请我们我们的记忆
is the this is the the memory address
是，这是在内存地址
space that every Linux program sees and
空间每一个Linux程序将看到并
we're drawing addresses starting from
我们正在绘制从开始的地址
zero and going up increasing as we grow
零和往上走 ， 因为 我们 日益 壮大
up and every program is loaded at this
起来 ，每个程序都 在此装
the same address 0 X 4 0 0 0 0 0 and so
相同的地址0 X 4 0 0 0 0 0 等
the the code comes directly from the
该代码直接来自
object file the data comes directly from
对象文件直接从数据配
the object file and then that's followed
目标文件 ，然后将该，再接
by a runtime heat which is created and
通过其创建的运行时的热量和
managed by malloc so when you need
由malloc的，所以当你需要管理
dynamic dynamically need to allocate
动态动态需要分配
memory like using malloc that memory
存储器 等使用malloc该存储器
comes out of this heap which starts
出来的这堆哪个开始的
immediately following the the data
马上数据如下
segment and grows upwards the stack is
段和向上生长 的堆栈
at the very top of the visible memory
在可见内存 的最顶端
that's available to application programs
这是提供给应用程序
the memory above that is is restricted
以上是其中存储器被限制
to the kernel ok so if you try to access
内核 确定，所以如果 您尝试访问
those memory locations you'll get a seg
这些内存位置，你会得到一个SEG
fault and then the stack as we know
故障，然后堆栈，因为我们知道
grows down so this is managed and
所以，这是管理下的增长和
created at runtime and then there's this
在 运行时创建，然后有这个
region somewhere in this huge gap
在这个 巨大的缺口区域某处
between the stack and the heap there's a
栈和堆之间有一个
region for shared libraries so the dot n
区域为这样的点Ñ共享库
so files all get loaded into this this
所以文件都得到加载到这个这个
memory mapped region for shared
存储器映射区域共享
libraries now that the top of the heap
图书馆现在该堆的顶部
is indicated by this global variable
通过这个 全局变量表示
maintained by the kernel called break
内核叫破维护
vrk and the the top of the stack as we
VRK和堆在我们的上方
know is is maintained by the general
知道的是，在前述的维护
purpose register RSP now there's a
通用寄存器RSP现在有一个
little bit of a this is a little bit of
的这一点点 一点点
a simplification if you actually
如果你真的简化
look at the addresses returned by malloc
看看malloc返回的地址
there's actually a there's actually two
这事实上是在实际上有两家
heaps there's a heap up here and in the
堆有一堆在这里和在
high memory that grows down that's used
即向下增长高内存的二手
for large objects very large you know if
对大对象非常大的，你知道，如果
you now like a whole bunch of space and
你现在喜欢一大堆的空间，
then the heat that grows up is is
然后就是成长的热量
reserved for smaller smaller objects so
保留用于较小的较小的对象，从而
I'm not really sure why they do this I
我真的不知道他们为什么 这样做我
think it allows them to have separate
认为这让他们有独立的
allocation algorithms for large objects
分配算法对大对象
and small objects
和小物件
okay so one of the one of the real
真正的一个好了，一个
advantages of linking is that allows us
联优点是，它允许我们
to create libraries of things so it's
创造 的东西 图书馆 所以它的
always something we want to do as
总有一些事情我们想做的
programmers we always we always want to
程序员我们总是我们总是 希望
create abstractions and then present
创建抽象然后本
those abstractions to to users right and
这些抽象给用户的权利和
we do that by creating libraries
我们通过创建库
defining an API yes I think it just no
定义 API是的，我认为 它只是没有
no it actually that's a good question I
不，它实际上是一个很好的问题，我
the things I've done it just grows until
我所做过的一切，它 只是增长，直到
it runs out of memory right there so I
它运行的内存 就在 那里等我
don't think actually that's a really
实际上并不认为 这是一个真正的
good question I mean I've done those
好问题， 我的意思是我所做的那些
experiments and it it eventually reaches
实验和它，它最终到达
some limit yeah I don't I don't know
一些限制是啊，我不，我不知道
it's a very large number but I so
这是一个很大的数字，但我这样
you know as programmers we always want
你知道程序员 我们总是希望
to abstract define api's implement
抽象定义API的实现
package up those ATIS and make them
打包的 ATIS，让他们
available to to other programmers so how
提供给其他程序员所以如何
can we actually do that how can we make
我们实际上可以做到这一点，我们怎样才能使
commonly used functions available to
提供常用功能
other programmers well one thing given
其他程序员还有一两件事给
what we've learned so far you could just
我们已经学会为止 你可以只
take all the functions and put them all
采取的所有功能，并把他们所有
in a single big C file right and then
在一个大的C文件正确，然后
programmers would just link that C file
程序员只想链接C文件
into their into their programs that they
到他们到他们的计划， 他们
want to use them right another option
要使用他们的权利 的另一种选择
would be to take that might get kind of
将采取可能 得到一种
unwieldy if it's a big library right
笨拙的，如果它是一个巨大的图书馆权利
let's see has hundreds and hundreds of
让我们来看看有成百上千的
functions so another option would might
功能，因此另一种办法是可能
be to just take each function put it in
是只取各 功能把它放在
a separate file and then compile them
一个单独的文件，然后将它们编译
all together and compile and link them
一起，编译和链接它们
all together so this is more space and
所有在一起 ，这 是更大的空间，
time efficient than then our first
时间不是那么我们的第一个有效
option but it seems like it would be
选项，但现在看来似乎 会
burdensome on the programmer because the
繁重的程序员，因为
program would have to know where all
程序必须知道所有
these functions were and put them in
这些函数并把 它们在
make files would just be a lot of you
使文件也只是很多你
know this you could end up with a
知道这一点，你可以结束了一个
ridiculously large command line to GCC
大的离谱命令行GCC
so that the one solution to this problem
这样的一个解决 这个问题
it's a the first solution that the
它是第一个解决方案是，
developers of UNIX came up with is
UNIX的开发人员想出了IS
something call it static library so the
东西 称之为静态 库，因此
idea with a static library is that you
与 静态库 的想法 是，你
create this archive called the dot a
建立这个档案称为一个点
file which is it's just a collection of
文件， 该文件是它只是一个 集合
dot o files where each dot o file
点O文件，其中每个点o文件
contains a function ok so you take all
包含一个函数确定 ，所以你把 所有
the functions in your library you use
在您的图书馆 使用的功能
option two to create a bunch of dot o
选择两 到创建一批点邻
files and then you use a program called
文件，然后使用一个 名为程序
an archive or a R to take those dot o
存档 或A R 采取 这些点ö
files put them together in a all
文件把它们放在一起的所有
together in a big file called an archive
一起在一个 大的文件名为存档
out with a with a table of contents at
出了与表的内容
the beginning that tells you the offset
告诉 你的偏移量开始
of each one of the dot o file
点o文件中的每一个
okay so an archive is just this
好了，所以归档就是这
concatenated collection of dot o files
的点O文件级联集合
and then and then you link you pass that
然后，然后你链接您 传递
archive to the to the linker and it only
归档到的链接 ，只有它
takes the dot o files that are actually
采用的是实际上是点O文件
referenced and lengths them into the
引用和 长度他们进入
code right so it's a more efficient way
代码右所以它是一个更有效的方法
you can have a huge archive but like
你可以有一个巨大的 存档，但像
let's see but if you only call printf
让我们来看看，但如果你只调用 printf
the only dot o file you get is printf
你得到的唯一点Ø文件的printf
zero okay so the way this works is as
零 还好所以这种工作方式是
before we take we take all the functions
我们采取之前，我们把 所有的功能
we want to put in our library we run
我们希望把我们的图书馆 ，我们运行
them through our translators to get dot
他们通过我们的翻译得到点
o files we pass those to the archiver to
O文件我们通过那些归档到
get a the archive so in this case of Lib
获得存档所以在这种情况下，库中
C dot a and which has this code for
Ç点和具有此 代码
printf that we might want to use right
我们可能要使用 正确 的printf
and so we can we can we can recreate
所以我们可以，我们可以，我们可以重建
that archive anytime we want so if one
该归档随时都想要，所以如果一个
of these functions changes like say
这些 功能 的 改变就好说了
printf changes you just re archive the
printf的改变，你只需重新归档
dot recompile printf and then re archive
点重新编译的printf，然后重新归档
all of it dot o files so in let's see
所有的这点O文件所以让我们来看看
it's about 1500 object files and it's
这是关于1500的目标文件，它的
archived things like printf scanf simple
归档之类 的printf scanf的简单
integer math and there's also a math
整数运算，也有一个数学
library which has you know several
其中有你知道的几个库
hundred common functions for things like
对于像百个常用功能
floating point math sine cosine tangent
浮点运算的正余弦 正切
etc these libraries the convention is
等这些库的惯例是
that a library always is prefixed with
该图书馆总是有前缀
Lib L ID and then and then sort of
库11d中 ，然后再排序
there's some indication of what it what
有什么它的一些迹象是什么
it does
它
so now let's see how linking with these
所以现在我们来看看如何使用这些链接
static libraries of work so I I've
工作的静态库，所以我我有
created a little example here I've
在这里创造一个小例子中，我
created a library called Lib vector a
创建了一个名为 库矢量库
and it consists of functions that
它包含函数
manipulate vectors and this is a real
操纵载体，这是一个真正的
simple library just adds there's a
简单的库只是 增加了有一个
function to add two vectors x and y
功能添加两个矢量x 和y
together and return the result in Z and
一起和Z轴返回结果和
then another similar function that will
然后另一个类似的功能，将
do pairwise multiplication of two
做两成对的乘积
vectors so X I times y I equals Z I and
矢量所以XI乘以y I等于ZI和
now I compile these two programs and
现在我编译这两个程序
pack I want to package them into an
收拾我想将它们打包成一个
archive called lead vector a and then in
归档称为铅载体，然后在
my in my main program I'm going to call
我在我的主要节目， 我会 打电话到
one of those functions advic to add
的advic添加这些功能之一
these two vectors x and y together
这两个矢量x和y一起
so now what happens when we compile this
所以现在，当我们编译这个 会发生什么
this program we've already we've
这个计划我们已经我们已经
constructed the archive live dr. a from
构建归档 现场 博士。从一
ad zero and multi
广告零和多
and we pass that archive to the linker
我们传递 存档链接
along with our main to zero relocatable
随着我们的主要零重定位
objects file and we also pass it live CA
对象文件，我们也把它传递住 CA
which has the definition of which
其具有的定义
contains printf zero and anything else
包含printf 零和其他任何
that printf L might call so these three
这printf的大号可能会调用所以这三个
the linker detects the reference to
链接器检测到参考
advic the function add back and so it
advic功能添加回去，所以它
just pulls advocaat o out and and
只是拉阿德沃卡特Ø 出来，和
ignores the rest
忽略其他
similarly for printf dot o and then it
同样，对于printf的点O和然后
compiles all those main main to 0 add
编译所有的主力主攻 0添加
vector and printf dot o all together
矢量和printf点o所有一起
into this fully linked executable called
这个所谓的完全链接的可执行文件
prog to see for compiled time so we're
PROG 看到的 编译时间，让我们
doing this we're doing this link we're
这样做，我们正在做的这个环节我们
doing this this linking at compile time
在编译的时候这样做此链接
when we call a GCC now what the linker
当我们现在所说的GCC链接什么
does when it's when it's using static
确实，当它时， 它使用静态的
libraries it scans all the dot o files
库它会扫描所有的点O文件
and dot a files in order on the command
和斑点一个文件，以便在命令
line so you're just typing GCC and then
行，以便你 只是打字GCC然后
a list of dot o files and dot a CoA
点O文件列表，并点农委会
files in some words so so during the
在某些词的文件，以便使在
scan it keeps a list of the current
扫描它保持当前的列表
unresolved references right so if let's
解析引用正确的，所以如果让我们
say let's say it looks at main dot o
比如说我们说，它看起来在主要点Ø
first and there's a reference to printf
第一，有给printf参考
that's an unresolved reference because
这是一个悬而未决的参考，因为
printouts not not defined in main dot o
打印输出不不在主点Ò定义
so that goes in a list of undefined
使云中的不确定列表
references and at some point or another
在某一点或其他的引用和
as each new 0 file or dot a file is
因为每个新0文件或点文件是
encountered the linker tries to
遇到链接器会尝试
resolve its list of unresolved
解决其悬而未决的名单
references with the symbols that are
是与作为符号的引用
defined in that dot o file or dot a file
在该点o文件中定义或点文件
and then if there's any entries in the
然后如果有一个在任何条目
list at the end of the scan then there's
名单在 扫描的末尾，则有
an error okay so that the key here is
错误好了，所以，关键是这里
that the linker will try to resolve
链接器将尝试解决
these references from left to right on
从左至右这些引用
the command line and so this is another
命令行 ，因此这是另一
sort of important thing for you to know
那种重要的事情你就 知道
as programmers because the order that
作为程序员，因为为了使
you that you put your files on the
你，你穿上你的文件
command line actually makes a difference
命令行实际上有差别
okay so you can get sort of weird
好了，你 可以得到几分怪异
baffling linker errors if you if you use
莫名其妙的链接错误，如果你，如果你使用
the wrong order so for instance suppose
错误的顺序，以便例如假设
we've got a function an object module
我们已经有了一个函数的对象模块
called Lib test that calls a function
叫库测试调用一个函数
that's defined in and live Monday okay
这是一个在和现场 周一 定义 好吗
so these - L - Big L period that that
所以这些- L -比格·L时期，即
says to look for to look for a library
说去找找库
files in the current directory that's
在当前目录中这是文件
what the dot look there first and then
什么点看那里， 然后再
look in the normal places that you look
看在你看正常的地方
and the the - lowercase L that's a it's
而在-小写的L，这是一个很
like an abbreviation we could replace
喜欢的缩写，我们可以更换
this with just the fully spelled out vid
这个只用全拼的 VID
mind is okay but you'll see this this
心是好的 ，但你会看到这本
lowercase L used a lot so so Lib test
小写L中使用的很多，所以这样库测试
calls a function that's declared in in
调用被声明在一个函数
live mind dot a so the linker looks at
住心中有点的因此链接看
it looked at the unresolved symbols in
它看起来在未解决的符号
Lib test dot o and it detects that
库测试点O和它检测到
there's this unresolved function let's
有这个悬而未决的功能，让我们
say it's called foo I know it's it's
说这叫做foo我知道这是它的
called lid fun so and it puts it on the
所谓盖的乐趣所以，它把它的
list and then it goes on to the next
列出， 然后 继续到 下一个
command line entry and that's lid line
命令行进入，这就是盖线
dot a and in there it finds it finds
点一，并在那里找到它找到
this symbol of live phone and it
现场的手机，它这个符号
resolves the reference to that - lid
解析参照 该 - 盖
phone - the actual address
电话- 实际 地址
the relocated address now if we switch
现在，如果我们切换搬迁地址
the order and we we put lib mind on a
顺序 和我们我们把 LIB 心灵 上
first followed by lib to zero well
第一随后LIB 到 零以及
there's there's no unresolved references
还有的没有分辨的引用
in this library right it's just a
在这个库 的权利，它只是一个
collection of function definitions so it
的函数定义集合，这样它
there's no unresolved references so the
有没有未解决的引用，这样的
linker looks at that that's all good and
连接着眼于这一切都很好，
then it looks at lib test dot oh now
然后，它着眼于LIB 测试点 哦， 现在
there's an unresolved reference to to
有一个未解决的参考，以
live fun but we're out of we're at the
生活乐趣，但我们出门 ，我们的是在
end of the command line so that's the
在命令 行 的结束 ，这样的的
linker err so you get this you get this
连接犯错，所以你得到这个你得到 这个
really cryptic error message and if you
真正神秘的错误消息，如果您
didn't know about this ordering rule you
不知道这个排序规则你
wouldn't have any idea how to debug it
不会有任何想法如何调试它
okay so the static libraries are kind of
好了，所以静态库是一种
the old-fashioned solution that the
老式 的 解决方案是，
modern solution is to use dynamic
现代的解决方案是使用动态
libraries are shared a shared library so
库共享的共享库，以便
the reason the reason there's this sort
之所以有这种原因
of newer form of libraries that static
图书馆的新形式静
libraries have some some disadvantages
图书馆有一些一些缺点
so every if you compile with static
所以每次如果用静态编译
libraries then every every function that
库然后每家每户功能
uses print out of which it or every
使用打印出它或每隔的
program that uses printf has to have a
使用 printf的程序有有
copy of printf okay but almost every
printf的副本还可以，但几乎每一个
every program uses printf right so
每一个程序使用printf的权利，使
there's shared shared libraries allow
还有的共享共享库允许
provide a mechanism where they can just
提供一种机制， 在那里他们可以只
be one wherever there's just one
是一个只要有只有一个
instance of a shared library member like
一个共享库成员的实例像
like printf and and every program
像printf和和每个程序
running on the system will share that
在 系统 上 运行 将分享
one copy
一个副本
so that's the that's sort of the big big
所以这是这是那种大的大
disadvantage of this potential
这种潜在的缺点
duplication so shared libraries are
重复这样的共享库是
different in the sense that they contain
在这个意义上，它们包含不同
code and data that are linked and loaded
代码和数据被链接和加载的
into the program not when it's not when
进入程序 而不是当它不是时
it's compiled and linked and into a
它的编译和链接，进入一个
executable object file but actually when
可执行目标文件 ，但实际上，当
the program is loaded into the system so
程序被加载 到系统中，以便
linking of references to shared library
共享库引用的链接
objects is deferred until the program is
对象被推迟， 直到 程序
actually loaded into into memory until
实际上装入到内存中，直到
the executable object file is actually
可执行的 目标文件 实际上 是
loaded into memory and this can either
加载到存储器中，这既可以
and it can even happen it can happen
它甚至可能发生它可以发生
when the program is actually loaded into
当程序实际加载到
memory but it can also happen at runtime
内存，但它也可能发生在运行时
anytime at runtime so you can be you can
随时在运行，所以你可能是你能
be running a program and that program
正在运行 的程序和 程序
can arbitrarily decide to load a
可以任意 决定加载
function that's declared in a shared
这是一个在共享声明功能
library okay I'll show you that it's
库好吧，我会告诉你 ，这是
really cool now these things are often
真的很酷，现在这些东西 往往 是
called they're called shared libraries
叫他们是所谓的共享库
they're called dynamic link libraries
他们是所谓的动态链接库
like in Windows they're called DLLs dot
如同在Windows中他们是所谓的DLL文件点
ISO files they're all referenced the
ISO文件，它们都引用
same thing
一样
okay so that just like I said you can be
还好，这样 就跟我 说，你可以
the dynamic linking can occur when the
动态链接时可出现
program's loaded or after it's loaded
程序的加载或它的加载后
and actually running and there's a sort
和实际运行 ，并有一个排序
of big deal that shared library routines
大的交易，共享库例程
can be shared by multiple processes and
可以由多个进程共享和
we'll look at this this will make sense
我们来看看这个，这将是有意义
when we look at virtual memories so
当我们看到 虚拟记忆，所以
don't don't worry about that now but but
不是不担心 ，但现在却
here's how the process works
这里的过程如何 工作
so we first we have to create instead of
所以我们首先我们要创造，而不是
creating an archive we create a shared
创建我们创建一个共享的归档
library so our lid vector routines
库，所以我们 盖矢量程序
instead of creating an archive a file we
而不是创建一个存档 文件，我们
create a shared a dot iso file using the
创建共享使用一个点iso文件
using the shared argument to GCC so we
使用共享参数 GCC 所以我们
take our two input functions add Zac and
把我们的两个输入功能添加和扎克
molbeck and share it says to create and
molbeck 并分享它说，创建和
we're telling GCC to create a shared
我们告诉GCC创建共享
library and place it in live dr. dot fo
库并将其放置在 现场博士。点 FO
okay and so and there's also that the
好吧所以还有还有，该
the C the C developers created a
在C中的C语言开发创建的
function of shared library called Lib C
称为库Ç共享库的功能
so that contains printf and all and
使包含printf和所有与
other standard library functions so we
其他的标准库函数，所以我们
take our program main - this is the same
把我们的程序主 -这是一样的
program that calls adzick and we compile
程序 调用 adzick和我们编译
it into main to zero and we passed main
入主为零， 我们通过主
to zero and these dot s0 files to the
到零，这些点S0文件到
linker now the linker doesn't at this
连接器提供了链接器不会在这
point it doesn't actually copy let's say
点它实际上并没有复制假设
we're using advic or printf it doesn't
我们使用advic或printf的 它不
actually copy those functions or do
实际上复制这些功能或做
anything with them in the executable it
他们中的任何可执行它
just makes a note in the symbol table
只是让音符符号表
that those functions will need to be the
这些功能将需要的
references to those functions will need
这些函数的引用将需要
to be resolved when the program is
当程序得到解决
loaded okay so it
装好了，所以它
it puts in a relocation entry it says
它把在搬迁进入它说
fix this stuff when you load the program
当你加载程序解决此问题的东西
so it's partially linked but it's not
所以它的部分链接，但它不是
fully linked you can't take that you
完全挂钩，你不能把你
can't take a program
不能把一个程序
you can't take a executable file that
你不能把一个可执行 文件
was dynamically linked and load it
被动态链接和加载
directly what you what you do is the
直接你什么，你要做的就是
loader which is the X X ee system call
装载机这是XX EE系统调用
and we'll learn more about that but just
我们会更多地了解 这一点，但 只是
this is just a sis call that loads loads
这只是加载载荷一个SIS通话
executables into memory and runs them
可执行文件到内存中，并运行它们
the loader takes the executable and then
装载机取可执行文件，然后
it takes the shared data so files that
它需要共享数据，使文件
this this program needs
这个这个程序需要
cade also made when the linker also made
凯德 也取得了当连接也做了
a note of which data so files it needs
记下哪些数据，这样文件就需要
so the loader calls the dynamic linker
所以加载器调用动态链接
which takes those deso files and then
这需要那些DESO文件 ，然后
actually resolves all the references to
实际上解析到的所有引用
any unresolved reference ok so the
任何未解决的引用 确定故
address of advic the add vac and printf
advic附加VAC和printf的地址
functions isn't determined until the
功能没有被确定直到
program is loaded and by that and it
程序被加载并且由它
isn't determined by the dynamic linker
不是由动态链接程序确定
until the program is loaded so that the
直到程序被 加载， 使得
dynamic linker does it goes through a
动态链接程序它会经过一个
similar process that the static linker
类似的过程，静态链接
did sort of fixing up references to add
没有那种固定起来引用添加
back at references to to printf and then
回到引用给printf，然后
at that point the binary the binary is
在这一点上的二进制二进制是
in it is in a form that can be executed
在它是一种 形式的可 被 执行
directly so question
这样直接的问题
that it can I don't work
它可我不 工作
yeah well what if you look at the bottom
是的，你也会认真考虑，如果在底部
where you'd like weird is that no look
您希望奇怪的是， 没有看
at you blue violet look at your finger
你蓝紫看看你的手指
and b0s if okay the question is what
和b0s如果没事的问题 是什么
happens if you include a file so
情况如果 包括文件，以便
includes are handled by the C
包括被由C处理
preprocessor so they're gone they're
预处理所以他们走了 他们
long gone by the time them by the time
长由时间他们的时候了
the linker gets around to it okay so the
链接得到解决它好了，所以在
C preprocessor just takes sharp sign
C预处理器只需要锋利的标志
define sharp sign include and and
限定尖锐符号包括与和
interprets those and outputs another C
解释那些，并输出另一种C
program so if you if you include a file
程序，所以如果你，如果你有一个文件
the C preprocessor just takes that file
C预处理器只需要该文件
and just expands it and the output seat
， 只是其扩展和输出 座
program contains an expanded version of
程序中包含的扩展版本
all the files that you included
所有你 包含的文件
now what's really cool is that you can
现在真正酷的 是，你 可以
also do this dynamic linking at runtime
也做在运行时，这个动态链接
so what I showed you before we're doing
所以我向您展示我们在做之前
it at load time but you can also
它在加载时间，但你也可以
arbitrarily decide to to load link and
擅自决定加载链接，
call a function from a shared from a
根据从一个共享调用一个函数
from any function defined in a dot iso
从以点ISO定义的任何功能
file and the way you do it is there's a
文件，你做的方式是有一个
there's an interface called dl open
有一个名为DL开放的接口
that's in Lib C that allows you to do
这是 在库ç，让你做
this and so let's say we want to this is
这一点，让我们说 ，我们希望这是
this is our main program and just like
这是我们的主要程序，并就像
before we want to call adzick okay but
之前，我们要调用adzick不错，但
advic now is defined in it in a dot iso
advic现在它定义在一个点异
file the exact same dot SL file that we
文件完全相同的点SL文件，我们
generated before when we compile so
当我们编译所以 之前生成
we'll call this dll C when we compile
当我们编译我们将调用这个DLLÇ
this program DLL dot C we have no we
这个程序DLL C点，我们有没有我们
have no idea that it's going to call a
不知道这是怎么回事 调用
function from from lib dr. D so we just
从LIB DR功能。 D，使得我们 只
compile it as those standalone C C
编译为那些独立CC
program within this program though we
这个方案虽然我们计划之内
declare a pointer a function pointer
声明指针的函数 指针
called advic and we give the prototype
所谓advic我们给原型
for this function its pointers cities so
这个函数指针， 它 使城市
it's two input arrays the output array
它的两个输入数组输出数组
on the size and then first we
在尺寸，然后第一我们
dynamically load the shared library that
动态加载共享库
contains the function we want so we call
包含我们 希望，所以我们调用 函数
DL open and we say load up this this dot
DL开放的和我们说加载了这个这个点
s L file into memory so that I can call
。S L文件到内存中，这样我可以调用
a function but don't resolve you know
功能，但不解决，你知道
don't worry don't worry about the
不用担心不担心
resolving the references to functions
解析为函数的引用
until I actually tell you - that's the
直到我真正告诉你-这就是
lazy part and so what what this deal
懒惰的一部分，所以什么什么这个交易
open returns a handle that that then you
打开返回的句柄是，那么你
use in subsequent calls okay so if we
在后续调用使用好了，所以如果 我们
don't if the handle as no there was some
不，如果把手，因为没有有一些
kind of error like maybe maybe this data
一种错误的喜欢，也许也许这个数据
so file doesn't exist
所以文件不存在
so once we've opened that data so file
所以一旦我们开放数据，以便文件
then we use DL cm with the handle so
然后我们用DL厘米 ，手柄等等
this and then we we give it as we passes
这一点，那么我们我们给它，因为我们通过
a string the name of the function that
字符串函数的名称
we want to invoke and we get what we get
我们要调用，我们得到了什么，我们得到
back from the L sent as a pointer to
从 L 回 送作为指针以
that function and then we can we can use
该功能，然后我们可以，我们可以使用
that function just like any other
该功能就像任何其他
function so we can use that function
功能，所以我们可以使用该功能
pointer and we call it just as Ella
指针我们称之为就像 艾拉
where it's statically defined function
它是静态定义的函数
so you can see this is real very
所以你可以看到这是真的很
powerful technique okay so let's let's
强大的技术好了，让我们，让我们
finish the last little bit of the class
完成课程 的最后一点
I want to show you it to try to convince
我想 向你展示它试图说服
you that linking is is actually
您链接实际上是
interesting which is kind of a hard sell
有趣的是一种强买强卖的
sometime yes question yes
有时是 问题是
no it's that's how now you just it's
没有它那怎么现在你只是它的
it's declared as a function pointer and
它被声明为函数 指针和
you then you just you just you just use
你，那么你只是你只是你 只需要使用
the name of the function
该 函数 的名称
you have to dereference it or you just
你必须取消 对它 的引用 ，或者你
you call it you call the function by
你怎么称呼它，你通过调用函数
just using that that that function
只是使用这项职能
pointer name okay just like I did
指针名正确，就像我做
if you dereference it I just get back a
如果取消引用它，我只是拿回
pointer value you get back the address
指针值你回来的地址
of that function all right so it's kind
该函数的所有权利，使的它是一种
of a hard sell to that to convention of
强买强卖 到 到公约
linking is is interesting but I'm going
联是有趣的，但 我会
to try ok so there's there's this
所以有有 此 尝试 确定
powerful technique called in library
叫库强大的技术
inter positioning and the goal is to
间的定位和 目标是
intercept function calls from from
拦截功能从通话
libraries and do something intercept
图书馆，做一些拦截
them for some reason right so what we
他们出于某种原因正确所以我们
typically want to do is intercept the
通常希望做的是拦截
function call maybe record some to some
函数调用可能记录一些一些
statistics or do some error checking and
统计或者做一些错误检查 和
then call the real function as intended
然后调用真正的功能如预期
right so so the idea is we're going to
右 所以这样的想法是，我们要
create wrappers and when the program
创建包装和当程序
when a program calls a function what
当程序调用的函数 是什么
we're going to do is we're going to
我们要做的是我们要
execute its wrapper instead okay and
执行它的包装，而不是 很好，而且
we're going to do it without changing
我们要做到这一点不改变
any of the source
任何来源的
now there there's a lot of reasons
现在有很多 的原因
there's a lot of applications for this
有很多的这种应用
that the neatest ones that that I know
是最巧妙的那些，我知道
is that these facebook engineers so
是这些 Facebook的 工程师如此
we're trying to deal with this year-long
我们正在努力解决这个问题长达一年
blog in the Facebook iPhone app and
博客在 Facebook 的 iPhone应用程序和
nobody could figure out what was going
没有人能弄清楚是怎么回事
on and they figured it out using library
对 他们想通了利用图书馆
inter positioning they figured out that
间的定位 ，他们想通了，
there was something in the network stack
有什么东西在网络堆栈
writing to the wrong location they
写入错误的位置，他们
figured it out by intercepting all the
想通了拦截所有
calls from their Facebook app that did
从他们的 Facebook应用程序，调用做
rights so things like right right to the
权利所以像 向右 向右
EP right so they just they intercepted
EP权利，使他们只是他们截获
all those calls and then they were able
所有这些电话， 然后他们能
to when they looked at the arguments and
当他们看着的参数和
how those functions were being called
这些功能是如何被称为
they determine the error you can also
他们判断错误 ，你也可以
use it for monitoring and profiling like
用它来监控和分析一样
so if you want to know like how many
所以，如果你想知道像多少
times different functions get calls you
时代不同的功能让你通话
can you can do you can interpose we use
你可以可以做你可以设置我们使用
it for for generating address traces so
它用于产生地址迹线，以便
your Malak when you do your malik labs
您马拉克当你做你的马利克实验室
later in the semester you're going to be
后来在学期你将成为
evaluating your malik using a traces
评估使用的痕迹您马利克
that we generated from real programs
我们从实际的程序产生
using this inter positioning technique
使用这种间定位技术
alright so we we enter post on all the
好了 ， 所以 我们大家对所有 的 输入后
malloc and free calls in like netscape
在如Netscape malloc和免费电话
ID and then we just recorded what
ID，然后我们就记录什么
addresses and and sizes Malik was was
地址和和尺寸马利克是为
returning and what what blocks free was
返回，什么是什么块免费
freeing up and we just created a trace
解放了，我们 刚刚创建的跟踪
of those and and then so let me show you
那些和再这么让我告诉你
how you would do this so the idea let's
你会怎么做这样的想法，让我们
say we have this main program and the
比方说我们有这个主程序和
idea is to trace all the malloc and free
想法是跟踪所有的malloc和free
calls so there's one malloc call and
调用所以有一个malloc调用和
there's one free call and we want to
还有一个免费电话，我们希望
know what these addresses are and we
知道这些地址是和我们
want to know what these sizes are so we
想知道这些尺寸，所以我们
can do this at either compile time link
可以做到这一点编译时链接
time or run time to do it at compile
时间或运行时间去做编译
time we first write wrapper functions
一次，我们先写包装函数
called my malloc and my free where my
打电话给我的malloc和我的自由我的地方
malloc call
malloc调用
the real malloc function and then it
真正的malloc函数，然后将其
prints out the size that it was called
打印出的大小，它被称为
and the address that malloc returned
和地址 malloc返回
okay so this when we run our program it
好了，所以这个时候我们运行它的程序
will it will print out these all these
将它打印出这些所有这些
addresses and it does the same thing for
地址和它做同样的事情
free and then here's the trick in malloc
自由 ，那么这里的malloc的诀窍
H we we define malloc to be my malloc
我们定义的malloc ^ h我们是我的malloc
okay and free to be my free and then we
还好和自由是我的自由，那么我们
give the prototype for it so the
给原型它，因此
compiler doesn't get confused and then
编译器不会感到困惑，然后
we compile compile my malloc C into a
我们编译编译我的mallocÇ成
dot o file and then we call week then we
点o文件，然后我们称之为星期，然后我们
complete we call our program which is is
完成我们调用程序，该程序是
our main program int duxi for inner
我们的 内心主程序INT duxi
positioning and we call that and here's
定位和我们称之为和这里的
the trick we call it with the - cap I
我们与叫它的伎俩-盖 我
argument and we say look for any include
争论和我们说一下对于任何包括
files in the current directory okay so
在当前目录下好了，所以文件
this was similar to that l - CapTel
这是类似于 L - CapTel
argument but because we tell GCC to look
的说法，但因为我们告诉GCC看
in the current directory first so this
在当前目录第一所以这
is sort of where the inner positioning
排序是其中 内定位 的
happens just because when it does that
发生在它，只是因为
it's going to it's going to find a it's
它会它会找到它的
going to find a library called malloc H
要找到一个名为 的malloc ^ h 库
I mean a dot H file called malloc dot H
我 的意思是 叫的malloc 点H A点.h文件
and so all the calls to malloc will be
因此所有的malloc调用会
translated by the C preprocessor to my
通过C预处理程序来翻译我的
malloc so when we run this it prints out
malloc的，所以当我们运行这个它打印 出
the the trip malloc and free trace
该行程malloc和free 跟踪
now we can also do this at link time so
现在我们也可以在链接时这样做，所以
we can tell see in order to do this we
我们可以告诉看到，为了 做到这一点，我们
had to get access to the we had to
曾去访问，我们不得不
compile the program we didn't have to
编译 我们没有 给 程序
change it but we had to compile it we
改变它 ，但我们不得不编译我们
can use link time that are positioning
可以使用链接时被 定位
its to avoid that that that compilation
它避免 该该编译
so the way this works we define our
所以这种工作方式我们定义
wrapper functions with this special name
这个特殊的名字包装函数
underscore underscore wrap malloc and
强调下划线包装malloc和
this calls the real malloc function and
这就叫真正的malloc函数和
then prints out the information and then
然后打印出的信息， 然后
at link time then we do the inter
在链接时，然后我们做了 间
positioning by calling the linker with
定位通过调用链接器
this special
这个特殊的
- WL argument and so what this does the
- WL参数，所以这是什么 一样的
- WL flag to GCC says hey take what
- WL标志GCC说哎采取什么
follows the argument that follows or
得出如下参数或
place all the commas with spaces and
把所有的用逗号和空格
then invoke the linker with this
然后调用这个链接
argument okay so what we're doing is
争论好了，所以我们正在做的事情是
passing a linker arguments to the linker
传递一个连接参数的链接
and this - - wrap argument to the linker
这- - 包装参数的链接
it tells the linker to resolve all
它告诉连接器解决所有
references to malloc as the underscore
引用的malloc下划线
underscore wrap malloc and all
强调包装的malloc和所有
references to underscore real malloc -
引用强调真正的malloc -
should be resolved as malloc okay so
应该被解析为malloc的好了，
anywhere in the program where we call
在我们调用程序的任何地方
malloc it will be resolved to underscore
MALLOC 它 会被解析为下划线
underscore wrap malloc and it will
强调包装的malloc，它会
invoke our wrapper and then the wrapper
调用我们的包装，然后包装
calls real malloc which which by because
调用真正的malloc这其中的原因
of this flag resolves to the actual
这个标志解析为实际的
malloc routine now here you can also in
常规的malloc现在在这里你还可以 在
the really the really amazing thing is
真的真的令人惊奇的 是
you can also do this inter positioning
你也可以做到 这间定位
it load timer and run time when the
其 加载计时器，并且 当 运行 时间
program is loaded so you don't even need
程序被 加载 ，所以你甚至不需要
access to the dot o files all you need
接入点O文件，所有你需要
is access to the executable right and
是获得可执行的权利和
for every program we've access to the
每一个程序 ，我们已经 获得了
executable so think about that we can
可执行这样想来，我们可以
take any program and we can interpose on
采取任何程序，我们可以设置在
its library calls at runtime
它的库调用在运行时
so the way we do this is we write the
所以我们这样做的方法是我们写的
wrapper function now uses the DL sim
包装函数现在 使用DL SIM卡
call that we saw before and we call it
调用我们以前看到我们称之为
with a special function the special
具有特殊功能的特殊
argument called
参数来调用
next and we silver and what this is
接下来，我们银， 这是什么
saying is get the address of the real
说是得到真实的地址
knowledge okay so and what we're going
知识好了，而我们要去
to we're going to trick the linker into
到我们要 欺骗连接到
looking first to our our implementation
首先找我们我们的实现
of malloc but here we want the real one
的malloc 但在这里 ， 我们要的是真正 一个
so we're telling it to get to look in
所以 我们告诉它 去照照
the next place its next place that it
其次它的下一个地方，它
would normally look and and fetch the
一般看起来 与和取
the address of malloc so the result is a
的malloc的地址，这样的结果是
pointer a function pointer called malloc
指针的函数指针叫 的malloc
T and then we can just call that
T和那么我们可以只调用
function to get to call the Lipsy malloc
函数获取调用 malloc的Lipsy
and then print out the data okay we do
然后打印出来的 数据好了，我们做
the same thing for free say we use DF m
免费同样的事情说我们用 DF米
in exactly the same way for free and
恰好自由以同样的方式和
then the inter positioning now happens
那么定位间现在会发生
when the program is loaded so notice we
当程序被 加载 ，以便我们通知
built this our main program now int our
建立了这个我们的主程序现在 我们诠释
for runtime in a positioning we built it
在定位 运行时 ，我们建立了它
I'm sorry we created our dot SL file my
很抱歉，我们创建了我们的点SL文件我
Malachy so using the shared argument and
马拉奇所以使用共享参数，并
then and then we we compiled int int dot
再然后我们我们编辑了INT INT点
C into this executable called int R but
ç到这个可执行文件，称为INT R但
notice there's no mention of my malloc
注意有没有我的malloc提
dot SL anywhere and now the inner
点SL的任何地方，现在内
positioning happens when we actually run
定位发生在我们实际运行
the program and we do we we affect the
我们做我们 我们影响 程序
the inner positioning by setting an
内定位通过设置
environment variable called LD preload
所谓LD预紧环境变量
to my Malachy so and so well this is a
我马拉奇某某好，这是一个
environment variable to tell us the
环境变量来告诉我们
dynamic linker to look first in the
动态链接看起来首位
value it looked first in the value of LD
看重它首先考虑在LD的价值
preload is a list of locations look
预紧力的位置查找列表
first in those locations when to resolve
首先在这些位置时解决
references and only only later look in
引用和仅只是后来在看
the
该
the normal system places so we're saying
系统正常的地方，这样我们在说
to look in my Malik dot so4 unresolved
看在我马利克点 SO4悬而未决
references first and then and then we're
引用，然后再然后我们
invoking so this isn't bash this is how
调用所以这不是来砸这是怎么了
you initialize an environment variable
初始化环境变量
so we're initializing it to my Malik
所以我们这初始化我马利克
data so and then we're loading and
数据左右，然后我们加载和
running the program and so the LD so all
运行，以便所有的程序等等LD
the references to Malik get turned into
到马利克引用都被转换为
the references to the rapper function
引用到说唱功能
the Malik function that we defined in in
我们在定义的函数马利克
our program ok so that's a so that's it
我们计划好了，所以这是 一个原来是这样
so that that inter positioning is a
以使得 除定位是一个
really cool technique and it's only it's
很酷的技术，它只是它的
only possible because of linkers so
因为接头的唯一可能使
alright so good
好吧 那么好
we'll see you on on Thursday and good
我们将在看到你在星期四和好
luck with your cash life
祝你生活现金